[
  {
    "question": "Suppose that the value of x is −4. What is the value of the expression (3x − 5) + x?",
    "final_answer": -21,
    "section": "Expressions, Relations, and Substitution",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A brownie recipe is asking for 350 grams of sugar, and a pound cake recipe requires 270 more grams of sugar than a brownie recipe. How many grams of sugar are needed for the pound cake?",
    "final_answer": 620,
    "section": "Translation",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The size of a compressed file is 1.74 MiB, while the size of the original uncompressed file is 5.5 times greater. What is the size of the uncompressed file, in MiB?",
    "final_answer": 9.57,
    "section": "Translation",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Margo is 5 years old and Ivan is 34 years older than Margo. How old is Ivan?",
    "final_answer": 39,
    "section": "Translation",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Alice runs 1.9 times faster than Bob, who runs at 4.7 mph. How fast does Alice run, in mph?",
    "final_answer": 8.93,
    "section": "Translation",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Tao’s first car was 3 times cheaper than his second car, and he bought his second car for 7899 dollars. How much was Tao’s first car?",
    "final_answer": 2633,
    "section": "Translation",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The profit of ACME Corporation in the second quarter was 8.84 billion dollars, which was 1.3 times greater than the profit in the first quarter. What was ACME’s profit in the first quarter?",
    "final_answer": 6.8,
    "section": "Properties of Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The width of a rectangle is 125 meters shorter than the length. Find the length if the width is 205 meters.",
    "final_answer": 330,
    "section": "Properties of Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The payout for playing a single number on a roulette table is 35 times greater than the bet. Cindy receives the payout of $3850. How much was Cindy’s bet?",
    "final_answer": 110,
    "section": "Properties of Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A history textbook costs $90, which is five times cheaper than an anatomy textbook. Find the price of the anatomy text.",
    "final_answer": 450,
    "section": "Properties of Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "According to NASA, the global land-ocean temperature index (average surface temperature of Earth) in 2016 is 1.26 ◦C greater than it was in 1920. Find the average temperature in 1920 if it was 0.99 ◦C in 2016.",
    "final_answer": -0.27,
    "section": "Properties of Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Damian’s age is one year less than twice the Colin’s age. How old is Colin, if Damian is 17 years old?",
    "final_answer": 9,
    "section": "Properties of Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob says to Alice: if you give me 3 apples and then take half of my apples away, then I will be left with 13 apples. How many apples do I have now?",
    "final_answer": 23,
    "section": "Properties of Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Alice works two jobs. Her full-time job pays four times more than her part-time job, and together they pay 3800 dollars per month. Find how much her full-time job pays per month.",
    "final_answer": 3040,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Rita bought rice and truffles a grocery store, and she paid $67.5 more for truffles than she paid for the rice. Find the price of rice if the total bill was $72.",
    "final_answer": 2.25,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Alice, Bob, and Charlie stand to inherit 12000 dollars, and the will stipulates that the inheritance is to be split in such a way that Bob gets two times more money than Alice, while Charlie should get 1600 dollars less than Alice. Find the inheritance amount for Alice.",
    "final_answer": 3400,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Katy invested some money into bonds, and the amount of interest earned after one year was 25 times smaller than the original investment. Find the interest if the total amount in her account is $546.",
    "final_answer": 21,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "An éclair has five times as many calories as a latte, and together they have 264 calories. Find how many calories an éclair has.",
    "final_answer": 220,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The width of a rectangular parking lot is 40 feet shorter than its length. Find the width of the lot if its perimeter is 640 feet.",
    "final_answer": 140,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider an astronomical triangle with sides a, b, and c, such that the length of the side b is 3 light-years longer the length of a, and the length of c is 6 times shorter than the length of a. Find the length of side a if the perimeter of the triangle is 55 light-years.",
    "final_answer": 24,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A monthly pass for light rail is 1.2 times cheaper than the a bundle with 20 day passes. Find the price of the monthly pass if the bundle costs $10 more than the monthly pass.",
    "final_answer": 50,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A bread recipe calls for a mix of bleached flour, whole wheat flour, and rye flour. The volume of whole wheat should be two times greater than the volume of bleached, and the volume of rye should be 1 cup less than the volume of bleached. Find the volume in cups for bleached flour if the recipe is asking for 15 cups of flour in total.",
    "final_answer": 4,
    "section": "Solving Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The number 21 is what percent of 70?",
    "final_answer": 30,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The number 330 is 120% of what number?",
    "final_answer": 275,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A department store puts up shirts on sale at 35% discount. Find the original price of a shirt before the discount if the new price is $26.",
    "final_answer": 40,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A fast food chain raised the price of the beef burger from $5 to $6, and lowered the price of the chicken burger from $6 to $5. Find the percent increase for the price of the beef burger.",
    "final_answer": 20,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Suzy earned $208 in tips after 20% income tax. What was her pre-tax income?",
    "final_answer": 260,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A department store puts dresses up for sale at 30% discount. If the discounted price of a dress is $42, what was the original price before the discount?",
    "final_answer": 60,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Alice invested $1230 into a savings account with 1.4% monthly interest rate. What is the balance in the account after one month?",
    "final_answer": 1247.22,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Brent paid $5824 for a car, and this price included the 4% sales tax. How much did the car cost before the sales tax was applied?",
    "final_answer": 5600,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Roger paid $238 for a webcam during a 15%-off sale. Find the original price of the webcam.",
    "final_answer": 280,
    "section": "Percent",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan can grade 25 quizzes per hour. Find how many quizzes Ivan can grade in 4 hours.",
    "final_answer": 100,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Taylor makes 18 dollars per hour at her job. Find how many dollars Taylor earns in 3.5 hours.",
    "final_answer": 63,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Uri can walk 7 km in 2 hours. Find how many kilometers Uri can walk per hour.",
    "final_answer": 3.5,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Apu takes the express train from Springfield to Capital City, and a regular train on his way back from Capital City to Springfield. The express completes the trip in 4 hours 30 minutes, while the regular train covers the same distance in 6 hours. Find the speed of the express, in miles per hour, if the express runs 15 miles per hour faster.",
    "final_answer": 60,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Kay and July are opening the incoming mail together, with the goal of processing 400 envelopes. Find how many hours they need to complete the task if Kay can process 15 envelopes per hour, and July can process 35 envelopes per hour.",
    "final_answer": 8,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "One morning Aristotle starts walking from Athens to Megara, and at the same time Socrates starts on a journey from Megara to Athens. Being younger, Aristotle is walking 1.8 times faster than Socrates. After a 5 hour journey, they meet somewhere in the middle of the way. Find the speed of Aristotle, in km per hour, if the total distance between Athens and Megara is 42 km.",
    "final_answer": 5.4,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The top speed of a bullet train is 210 km per hour. Find how many hours it takes to travel 168 km at top speed.",
    "final_answer": 0.8,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A standard computer hard drive rotates at 5400 revolutions per minute. Find the number of revolutions over 10 seconds.",
    "final_answer": 900,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Eve typed up a 4050 word document over two and a half hours. Find Eve’s typing rate in words per minute.",
    "final_answer": 27,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Jamie charges $80 per hour for her paralegal work. Find how many hours she has to work in order to earn $2000.",
    "final_answer": 25,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "It takes Bongo two and a half hours to mow the front lawn. Find how many times he can mow the same lawn in 40 hours.",
    "final_answer": 16,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Alice paddled for 3 hours upstream and then for 2 hours downstream. When going downstream, her speed was 10 mph greater than her speed when going upstream. The total distance traveled was 30 miles. How fast did Alice travel upstream, in mph?",
    "final_answer": 2,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Ridwan can plant 4 trees per hour, and Sue can plant 5.5 trees per hour. Find how many hours they need to plant 285 trees, if they are working together.",
    "final_answer": 30,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A passenger and a freight train start toward each other at the same time from two points 300 miles apart. If the rate of the passenger train exceeds the rate of the freight train by 15 miles per hour, and they meet after 4 hours, what must the rate of the passenger be, in miles per hour?",
    "final_answer": 45,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Lab 1 can process blood samples 3 times faster than Lab 2. Working together, the two labs can process 84 samples over 7 days. Find the rate of work for Lab 1, in samples per day.",
    "final_answer": 9,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Two automobiles started at the same time from a point, but traveled in opposite directions. Their rates were 25 and 35 miles per hour respectively. After how many hours were they 180 miles apart?",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Applications",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Suzy pays $111 for an order of 4 black printer cartridges and 7 color cartridges. When supplies start running low, she goes back to the same store and pays $126 for an order of 3 black and 10 color cartridges. Find the price of one black cartridge.",
    "final_answer": 12,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A chemist receives an order for 10 liters of 48% isopropyl solution, that is, a solution consisting of 48 parts of isopropyl alcohol and 52 parts of water by volume. The stockroom only has some 15% solution and some 70% solution. How many liters of the 15% solution is needed in order to fulfill the order?",
    "final_answer": 4,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Charlie has in his coin jar a certain number of quarters and nickels. There are 77 coins in the jar, and together they are worth $6.05. Find how many quarters are in the jar.",
    "final_answer": 11,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A collection of dimes and quarters is worth $15.25. There are 103 coins in all. How many of dimes are there?",
    "final_answer": 70,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "There were 429 people at a play. Admission was $1 each for adults and 75 cents each for children. The receipts were $372.50. How many children attended?",
    "final_answer": 226,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A total of $27000 is invested, part of it at 12% and the rest at 13%. The total interest after one year is $3385. How much was invested at 12%?",
    "final_answer": 12500,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A coin bank contains nickels and dimes. The number of dimes is 10 less than twice the number of nickels. The total value of all the coins is $2.75. Find the number of nicklels in the bank.",
    "final_answer": 15,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A total of $9000 is invested, part of it at 10% and the rest at 12%. The total interest after one year is $1030. How much was invested at 10%?",
    "final_answer": 2500,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "At a coin-operated laundromat, using the washer 6 times and then the dryer 6 times costs $13.50, while using the washer 4 times and then the dryer 8 times costs $12. Find the cost of one wash.",
    "final_answer": 1.5,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A tea that is 20% jasmine is blended with a tea that is 15% jasmine. How many pounds of 20% jasmine tea are needed to make 5 lb of tea that is 18% jasmine?",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A party with 3 adults and 2 children pays 45 dollars for their tickets at Acme Theater. Another party, with 4 adults and 4 children, pays 68 dollars. Find the price of one adult ticket.",
    "final_answer": 11,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Every Monday Helen shares coffee and donuts with the office where she works. One week Helen buys 4 cups of coffee and 6 donuts, and pays 18 dollars. The next week Helen buys 6 cups of coffee and 12 donuts, and pays 30 dollars. Find the price of one cup of coffee.",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Applications of Systems",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan’s math class has 1.2 times more students than Ivan’s statistics class. Find how many people are enrolled in the statistics class has if the math class has 30 students.",
    "final_answer": 25,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Bart, Millhouse, and Martin Prince saved up 149 dollars for a collectible comic book. Find how much money Bart saved up if Bart contributed 3 times less than Millhouse, and Martin contributed 9 dollars more than Millhouse.",
    "final_answer": 20,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A quantity increased by 14% and is now 171. Find the quantity before the increase.",
    "final_answer": 150,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A quantity decreased from 140 to 133. Find the percent decrease.",
    "final_answer": 5,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "John paid 24% income tax on the total income of $28,000. Find how much money John has made after tax.",
    "final_answer": 21280,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "A contractor buys a residential property, renovates it, and then sells (flips) it with 25% markup. If the the sale price is $160, 000, find how much the contractor has paid for the property.",
    "final_answer": 128000,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Shannon’s business serves 14 clients per day on average. Find the time needed to serve 518 clients, in days.",
    "final_answer": 37,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Two cars, a Lotus and a Renault, are 635 kilometers apart. They start at the same time and drive toward each other. The Lotus travels at a rate of 70 kilometers per hour and the Renault travels at 57 kilometers per hour. In how many hours will the two cars meet?",
    "final_answer": 5,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "Jane’s monthly car loan payment is one quarter of her monthly house loan payment. Find her monthly car loan payment rate, in dollars per month, if Jane pays 19200 dollars in total over the course of the year.",
    "final_answer": 320,
    "section": "Linear Equations",
    "source": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "In the morning, the temperature in Urbana, Illinois was 11 degrees. By mid-afternoon, the temperature had dropped to −9 degrees. What was the difference of the morning and afternoon temperatures?",
    "final_answer": 20,
    "section": "Multiply and Divide Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Mustangs football team received three penalties in the third quarter. Each penalty gave them a loss of fifteen yards. What is the number of yards lost?",
    "final_answer": 45,
    "section": "Multiply and Divide Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "On January  15, the high temperature in Anaheim, California, was  84°. That same day, the high temperature in Embarrass, Minnesota was  −12°. What was the difference between the temperature in Anaheim and the temperature in Embarrass?",
    "final_answer": 96,
    "section": "Multiply and Divide Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the first down, the Chargers had the ball on their 25-yard line. They lost 6 yards on the first-down play, gained 10 yards on the second-down play, and lost 8 yards on the third-down play. What was the yard line at the end of the third-down play?",
    "final_answer": 21,
    "section": "Multiply and Divide Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mayra has $124 in her checking account. She writes a check for $152. What is the new balance in her checking account?",
    "final_answer": -28,
    "section": "Multiply and Divide Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diontre has a balance of −$38 in his checking account. He deposits $225 to the account. What is the new balance?",
    "final_answer": 187,
    "section": "Multiply and Divide Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Javier owns 300 shares of stock in one company. On Tuesday, the stock price dropped $12 per share. What was the total effect on Javier’s portfolio?",
    "final_answer": -3600,
    "section": "Multiply and Divide Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Don purchased a bulk package of candy that weighs 5 pounds. He wants to sell the candy in little bags that hold 14 pound. How many little bags of candy can he fill from the bulk package?",
    "final_answer": 20,
    "section": "Visualize Fractions",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Field trip All the 5th graders at Lincoln Elementary School will go on a field trip to the science museum. Counting all the children, teachers, and chaperones, there will be 147 people. Each bus holds 44 people. How many busses will be needed?",
    "final_answer": 4,
    "section": "Add and Subtract Fractions",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Julian drinks one can of soda every day. Each can of soda contains 40 grams of sugar. How many kilograms of sugar does Julian get from soda in 1 year?",
    "final_answer": 14.6,
    "section": "Systems of Measurement",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The high temperature one day in Miami Beach, Florida, was 76° . That same day, the high temperature in Buffalo, New York was −8° . What was the difference between the temperature in Miami Beach and the temperature in Buffalo?",
    "final_answer": 84,
    "section": "Add and Subtract Integers",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The MacIntyre family recycled newspapers for two months. The two months of newspapers weighed a total of 57 pounds. The second month, the newspapers weighed 28 pounds. How much did the newspapers weigh the first month?",
    "final_answer": 29,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Randell paid $28,675 for his new car. This was $875 less than the sticker price. What was the sticker price of the car?",
    "final_answer": 29550,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Avril rode her bike a total of 18 miles, from home to the library and then to the beach. The distance from Avril’s house to the library is 7 miles. What is the distance from the library to the beach, in miles?",
    "final_answer": 11,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Eva’s daughter is 15 years younger than her son. Eva’s son is 22 years old. How old is her daughter?",
    "final_answer": 7,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a family birthday dinner, Celeste bought a turkey that weighed 5 pounds less than the one she bought for Thanksgiving. The birthday turkey weighed 16 pounds. How much did the Thanksgiving turkey weigh, in pounds?",
    "final_answer": 21,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Connor’s temperature was 0.7 degrees higher this morning than it had been last night. His temperature this morning was 101.2 degrees. What was his temperature last night?",
    "final_answer": 100.5,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ron’s paycheck this week was $17.43 less than his paycheck last week. His paycheck this week was $103.76. How much was Ron’s paycheck last week?",
    "final_answer": 121.19,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Denae bought 6 pounds of grapes for $10.74. What was the cost of one pound of grapes?",
    "final_answer": 1.79,
    "section": "Solve Equations using the Division and Multiplication Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Andreas bought a used car for $12,000. Because the car was 4-years old, its price was 3/4 of the original price, when the car was new. What was the original price of the car?",
    "final_answer": 16000,
    "section": "Solve Equations using the Division and Multiplication Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ramona bought 18 balloons for a party. She wants to make 3 equal bunches. How many balloons did she use in each bunch?",
    "final_answer": 6,
    "section": "Solve Equations using the Division and Multiplication Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Serena paid $12.96 for a pack of 12 pairs of sport socks. What was the price of pair of sport socks?",
    "final_answer": 1.08,
    "section": "Solve Equations using the Division and Multiplication Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "John’s SUV gets 18 miles per gallon (mpg). This is half as many mpg as his wife’s hybrid car. How many miles per gallon does the hybrid car get?",
    "final_answer": 36,
    "section": "Solve Equations using the Division and Multiplication Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Bea earned $11,700 commission for selling a house, calculated as 6/100 selling price. What was the selling price of the house?",
    "final_answer": 195000,
    "section": "Solve Equations using the Division and Multiplication Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rey is planning to drive from his house in San Diego to visit his grandmother in Sacramento, a distance of 520 miles. If he can drive at a steady rate of 65 miles per hour, how many hours will the trip take?",
    "final_answer": 8,
    "section": "Solve a Formula for a Specific Variable",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Megan is taking the bus from New York City to Montreal. The distance is 380 miles and the bus travels at a steady rate of 76 miles per hour. How long will the bus ride be, in hours?",
    "final_answer": 5,
    "section": "Solve a Formula for a Specific Variable",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kareem wants to ride his bike from St. Louis to Champaign, Illinois. The distance is 180 miles. If he rides at a steady rate of 16 miles per hour, how many hours will the trip take?",
    "final_answer": 11.25,
    "section": "Solve a Formula for a Specific Variable",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alejandra is driving to Cincinnati, 450 miles away. If she wants to be there in 6 hours, at what rate does she need to drive, in miles per hour?",
    "final_answer": 75,
    "section": "Solve a Formula for a Specific Variable",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philip got a ride with a friend from Denver to Las Vegas, a distance of 750 miles. If the trip took 10 hours, how fast was the friend driving, in miles per hour?",
    "final_answer": 75,
    "section": "Solve a Formula for a Specific Variable",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tan weighs 146 pounds. Minh weighs 15 pounds more than Tan. How much does Minh weigh?",
    "final_answer": 161,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Elissa earned $152.84 this week, which was $21.65 more than she earned last week. How much did she earn last week?",
    "final_answer": 131.19,
    "section": "Solve Equations Using the Subtraction and Addition Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Janet gets paid $24 per hour. She heard that this is 3/4 of what Adam is paid. How much is Adam paid per hour?",
    "final_answer": 32,
    "section": "Solve Equations using the Division and Multiplication Properties of Equality",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two-thirds of the children in the fourth-grade class are girls. If there are 20 girls, what is the total number of children in the class?",
    "final_answer": 30,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zachary has 25 country music CDs, which is one-fifth of his CD collection. How many CDs does Zachary have?",
    "final_answer": 125,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are 16 girls in a school club. The number of girls is four more than twice the number of boys. Find the number of boys.",
    "final_answer": 6,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Huong is organizing paperback and hardback books for her club’s used book sale. The number of paperbacks is 12 less than three times the number of hardbacks. Huong had 162 paperbacks. How many hardback books were there?",
    "final_answer": 58,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philip pays $1,620 in rent every month. This amount is $120 more than twice what his brother Paul pays for rent. How much does Paul pay for rent?",
    "final_answer": 750,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Laurie has $46,000 invested in stocks and bonds. The amount invested in stocks is $8,000 less than three times the amount invested in bonds. How much does Laurie have invested in bonds?",
    "final_answer": 13500,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sum of a number and eight is 12. Find the number.",
    "final_answer": 4,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sum of three times a number and eight is 23. Find the number.",
    "final_answer": 5,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Three times the sum of a number and nine is 12. Find the number.",
    "final_answer": -5,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Patty paid $35 for a purse on sale for $10 off the original price. What was the original price of the purse?",
    "final_answer": 45,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Minh spent $6.25 on five sticker books to give his nephews. Find the cost of each sticker book.",
    "final_answer": 1.25,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tom paid $1,166.40 for a new refrigerator, including $86.40 tax. What was the price of the refrigerator?",
    "final_answer": 1080,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dezohn and his girlfriend enjoyed a nice dinner at a restaurant and his bill was $68.50. He wants to leave an 18% tip. If the tip will be 18% of the total bill, how much tip should he leave?",
    "final_answer": 12.33,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The label on Masao’s breakfast cereal said that one serving of cereal provides 85 milligrams (mg) of potassium, which is 2% of the recommended daily amount. What is the total recommended daily amount of potassium?",
    "final_answer": 4250,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mitzi received some gourmet brownies as a gift. The wrapper said each brownie was 480 calories, and had 240 calories of fat. What percent of the total calories in each brownie comes from fat?",
    "final_answer": 50,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The average price of a gallon of gas in one city in June 2014 was $3.71. The average price in that city in July was $3.64. Find the percent decrease.",
    "final_answer": 1.9,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Geneva treated her parents to dinner at their favorite restaurant. The bill was $74.25. Geneva wants to leave 16% of the total bill as a tip. How much should the tip be?",
    "final_answer": 11.88,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Trong has 12% of each paycheck automatically deposited to his savings account. His last paycheck was $2165. How much money was deposited to Trong’s savings account?",
    "final_answer": 259.8,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "One serving of oatmeal has eight grams of fiber, which is 33% of the recommended daily amount. What is the total recommended daily amount of fiber, in grams?",
    "final_answer": 24.2,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bacon cheeseburger at a popular fast food restaurant contains 2070 milligrams (mg) of sodium, which is 86% of the recommended daily amount. What is the total recommended daily amount of sodium, in milligrams?",
    "final_answer": 2407,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "After 3 months on a diet, Lisa had lost 12% of her original weight. She lost 21 pounds. What was Lisa’s original weight, in pounds?",
    "final_answer": 175,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Yuki bought a dress on sale for $72. The sale price was 60% of the original price. What was the original price of the dress?",
    "final_answer": 120,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tim left a $9 tip for a $50 restaurant bill. What percent tip did he leave?",
    "final_answer": 18,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The nutrition fact sheet at a fast food restaurant says the fish sandwich has 380 calories, and 171 calories are from fat. What percent of the total calories is from fat?",
    "final_answer": 45,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Emma gets paid $3,000 per month. She pays $750 a month for rent. What percent of her monthly pay goes to rent?",
    "final_answer": 25,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tamanika got a raise in her hourly pay, from $15.50 to $17.36. Find the percent increase.",
    "final_answer": 12,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Annual student fees at the University of California rose from about $4,000 in 2000 to about $12,000 in 2010. Find the percent increase.",
    "final_answer": 200,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A grocery store reduced the price of a loaf of bread from $2.80 to $2.73. Find the percent decrease.",
    "final_answer": 2.5,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hernando’s salary was $49,500 last year. This year his salary was cut to $44,055. Find the percent decrease.",
    "final_answer": 11,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the campus coffee cart, a medium coffee costs $1.65. MaryAnne brings $2.00 with her when she buys a cup of coffee and leaves the change as a tip. What percent tip does she leave?",
    "final_answer": 21.2,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "At a school concert, the total value of tickets sold was $1,506. Student tickets sold for $6 each and adult tickets sold for $9 each. The number of adult tickets sold was five less than three times the number of student tickets sold. How many student tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 47,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Galen sold 810 tickets for his church’s carnival for a total of $2,820. Children’s tickets cost $3 each and adult tickets cost $5 each. How many children’s tickets did he sell?",
    "final_answer": 615,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Monica paid $8.36 for stamps. The number of 41-cent stamps was four more than twice the number of two-cent stamps. How many 41-cent stamps did Monica buy?",
    "final_answer": 20,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Henning is mixing raisins and nuts to make 10 pounds of trail mix. Raisins cost $2 a pound and nuts cost $6 a pound. If Henning wants his cost for the trail mix to be $5.20 a pound, how many pounds of raisins should he use?",
    "final_answer": 2,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The school play sold $550 in tickets one night. The number of $8 adult tickets was 10 less than twice the number of $5 child tickets. How many of adult tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 50,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The movie theater took in $1,220 one Monday night. The number of $7 child tickets was ten more than twice the number of $9 adult tickets. How many of child tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 110,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ice rink sold 95 tickets for the afternoon skating session, for a total of $828. General admission tickets cost $10 each and youth tickets cost $8 each. How many general admission tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 34,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The box office sold 360 tickets to a concert at the college. The total receipts were $4170. General admission tickets cost $15 and student tickets cost $10. How many general admission tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 114,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Julie went to the post office and bought both $0.41 stamps and $0.26 postcards. She spent $51.40. The number of stamps was 20 more than twice the number of postcards. How many $0.41 stamps did she buy?",
    "final_answer": 100,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maria spent $12.50 at the post office. She bought three times as many $0.41 stamps as $0.02 stamps. How many $0.41 stamps did she buy?",
    "final_answer": 30,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hilda has $210 worth of $10 and $12 stock shares. The numbers of $10 shares is five more than twice the number of $12 shares. How many $10 shares does she have?",
    "final_answer": 15,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lauren in making 15 liters of mimosas for a brunch banquet. Orange juice costs her $1.50 per liter and champagne costs her $12 per liter. How many liters of orange juice should she use for the mimosas to cost Lauren $5 per liter?",
    "final_answer": 10,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaapo is mixing Kona beans and Maui beans to make 25 pounds of coffee blend. Kona beans cost Kaapo $15 per pound and Maui beans cost $24 per pound. How many pounds of Kona beans should Kaapo use for his blend to cost him $17.70 per pound?",
    "final_answer": 17.5,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "As the treasurer of her daughter’s Girl Scout troop, Laney collected money for some girls and adults to go to a 3-day camp. Each girl paid $75 and each adult paid $30. The total amount of money collected for camp was $765. If the number of girls is three times the number of adults, how many girls paid for camp?",
    "final_answer": 9,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "An express train and a local train leave Pittsburgh to travel to Washington, D.C. The express train can make the trip in 4 hours and the local train takes 5 hours for the trip. The speed of the express train is 12 miles per hour faster than the speed of the local train. Find the speed of the express train, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 60,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Christopher and his parents live 115 miles apart. They met at a restaurant between their homes to celebrate his mother’s birthday. Christopher drove 1.5 hours while his parents drove 1 hour to get to the restaurant. Christopher’s average speed was 10 miles per hour faster than his parents’ average speed. What were the average speed of Christopher as he drove to the restaurant, in miles per hour?",
    "final_answer": 50,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two truck drivers leave a rest area on the interstate at the same time. One truck travels east and the other one travels west. The truck traveling west travels at 70 mph and the truck traveling east has an average speed of 60 mph. How many hours will they travel before they are 325 miles apart?",
    "final_answer": 2.5,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Katie Mae walks to school, it takes her 30 minutes. If she rides her bike, it takes her 15 minutes. Her speed is three miles per hour faster when she rides her bike than when she walks. What is her walking speed, in miles per hour?",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lilah is moving from Portland to Seattle. It takes her three hours to go by train. Mason leaves the train station in Portland and drives to the train station in Seattle with all Lilah’s boxes in his car. It takes him 2.4 hours to get to Seattle, driving at 15 miles per hour faster than the speed of the train. Find Mason’s speed, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 75,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two busses go from Sacramento for San Diego. The express bus makes the trip in 6.8 hours and the local bus takes 10.2 hours for the trip. The speed of the express bus is 25 mph faster than the speed of the local bus. Find the speed of the express bus, in mph.",
    "final_answer": 75,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Saul drove his truck 3 hours from Dallas towards Kansas City and stopped at a truck stop to get dinner. At the truck stop he met Erwin, who had driven 4 hours from Kansas City towards Dallas. The distance between Dallas and Kansas City is 542 miles, and Erwin’s speed was eight miles per hour slower than Saul’s speed. Find the speed of Saul, in mph.",
    "final_answer": 82,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sisters Helen and Anne live 332 miles apart. For Thanksgiving, they met at their other sister’s house partway between their homes. Helen drove 3.2 hours and Anne drove 2.8 hours. Helen’s average speed was four miles per hour faster than Anne’s. Find Helen’s average speed, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 57.2,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Elvira and Aletheia live 3.1 miles apart on the same street. They are in a study group that meets at a coffee shop between their houses. It took Elvira half an hour and Aletheia two-thirds of an hour to walk to the coffee shop. Aletheia’s speed is 0.6 miles per hour slower than Elvira’s speed. Find Elvira’s walking speed, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cindy and Richard leave their dorm in Charleston at the same time. Cindy rides her bicycle north at a speed of 18 miles per hour. Richard rides his bicycle south at a speed of 14 miles per hour. How many hours will it take them to be 96 miles apart?",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two busses leave Billings at the same time. The Seattle bus heads west on I-90 at a speed of 73 miles per hour while the Chicago bus heads east at a speed of 79 miles an hour. How many hours will it take them to be 532 miles apart?",
    "final_answer": 3.5,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lorena walks the path around the park in 30 minutes. If she jogs, it takes her 20 minutes. Her jogging speed is 1.5 miles per hour faster than her walking speed. Find Lorena’s walking speed, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cassius drives his boat upstream for 45 minutes. It takes him 30 minutes to return downstream. His speed going upstream is three miles per hour slower than his speed going downstream. Find his upstream speed, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 6,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Three-fourths of the people at a concert are children. If there are 87 children, what is the total number of people at the concert?",
    "final_answer": 116,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sum of a number and three is forty-one. Find the number.",
    "final_answer": 38,
    "section": "Use a Problem-Solving Strategy",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What number is 67% of 250?",
    "final_answer": 167.5,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "12.5% of what number is 20?",
    "final_answer": 160,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What percent of 125 is 150?",
    "final_answer": 120,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bill for Dino’s lunch was $19.45. He wanted to leave 20% of the total bill as a tip. How much should the tip be?",
    "final_answer": 3.89,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dolores bought a crib on sale for $350. The sale price was 40% of the original price. What was the original price of the crib?",
    "final_answer": 875,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Angel’s got a raise in his annual salary from $55,400 to $56,785. Find the percent increase.",
    "final_answer": 2.5,
    "section": "Solve Percent Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paulette has $140 in $5 and $10 bills. The number of $10 bills is one less than twice the number of $5 bills. How many $5 bills does she have?",
    "final_answer": 6,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A church luncheon made $842. Adult tickets cost $10 each and children’s tickets cost $6 each. The number of children was 12 more than twice the number of adults. How many adult tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 35,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "125 tickets were sold for the jazz band concert for a total of $1,022. Student tickets cost $6 each and general admission tickets cost $10 each. How many student tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 57,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ana spent $4.06 buying stamps. The number of $0.41 stamps she bought was five more than the number of $0.26 stamps. How many $0.41 stamps did she buy?",
    "final_answer": 8,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Marquese is making 10 pounds of trail mix from raisins and nuts. Raisins cost $3.45 per pound and nuts cost $7.95 per pound. How many pounds of raisins should Marquese use for the trail mix to cost him $6.96 per pound?",
    "final_answer": 2.2,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Gabe drives from Sacramento to Redding it takes him 2.2 hours. It takes Elsa 2 hours to drive the same distance. Elsa’s speed is seven miles per hour faster than Gabe’s speed. Find Gabe’s speed, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 70,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two busses leave Amarillo at the same time. The Albuquerque bus heads west on the I-40 at a speed of 72 miles per hour, and the Oklahoma City bus heads east on the I-40 at a speed of 78 miles per hour. How many hours will it take them to be 375 miles apart?",
    "final_answer": 2.5,
    "section": "Solve Uniform Motion Applications",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sondra is making 10 quarts of punch from fruit juice and club soda. The number of quarts of fruit juice is 4 times the number of quarts of club soda. How many quarts of fruit juice does Sondra need?",
    "final_answer": 8,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Graphing",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Molly is making strawberry infused water. For each ounce of strawberry juice, she uses three times as many ounces of water. How many ounces of strawberry juice does she need to make 64 ounces of strawberry infused water?",
    "final_answer": 16,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Graphing",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Enrique is making a party mix that contains raisins and nuts. For each ounce of nuts, he uses twice the amount of raisins. How many ounces of nuts does he need to make 24 ounces of party mix?",
    "final_answer": 8,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Graphing",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Leo is planning his spring flower garden. He wants to plant tulip and daffodil bulbs. He will plant 6 times as many daffodil bulbs as tulip bulbs. If he wants to plant 350 bulbs, how many tulip bulbs should he plant?",
    "final_answer": 50,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Graphing",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 88. The length is five more than twice the width. Find the length.",
    "final_answer": 31,
    "section": "Solving Systems of Equations by Substitution",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Heather has been offered two options for her salary as a trainer at the gym. Option A would pay her $25,000 plus $15 for each training session. Option B would pay her $10,000 + $40 for each training session. How many training sessions would make the salary options equal?",
    "final_answer": 600,
    "section": "Solving Systems of Equations by Substitution",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The perimeter of a rectangle is 84. The length is 10 more than three times the width. Find the length.",
    "final_answer": 34,
    "section": "Solving Systems of Equations by Substitution",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jackie has been offered positions by two cable companies. The first company pays a salary of $ 14,000 plus a commission of $100 for each cable package sold. The second pays a salary of $20,000 plus a commission of $25 for each cable package sold. How many cable packages would need to be sold to make the total pay the same?",
    "final_answer": 80,
    "section": "Solving Systems of Equations by Substitution",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mitchell currently sells stoves for company A at a salary of $12,000 plus a $150 commission for each stove he sells. Company B offers him a position with a salary of $24,000 plus a $50 commission for each stove he sells. How many stoves would Mitchell need to sell for the options to be equal?",
    "final_answer": 120,
    "section": "Solving Systems of Equations by Substitution",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Joe stops at a burger restaurant every day on his way to work. Monday he had one order of medium fries and two small sodas, which had a total of 620 calories. Tuesday he had two orders of medium fries and one small soda, for a total of 820 calories. How many calories are there in one order of medium fries?",
    "final_answer": 340,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Elimination",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Andrea is buying some new shirts and sweaters. She is able to buy 3 shirts and 2 sweaters for $114 or she is able to buy 2 shirts and 4 sweaters for $164. How much does a shirt cost?",
    "final_answer": 16,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Elimination",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The total amount of sodium in 2 hot dogs and 3 cups of cottage cheese is 4720 mg. The total amount of sodium in 5 hot dogs and 2 cups of cottage cheese is 6300 mg. How much sodium is in a hot dog, in mg?",
    "final_answer": 860,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Elimination",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Devon is 26 years older than his son Cooper. The sum of their ages is 50. Find Devon's age.",
    "final_answer": 38,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Jenna spent 10 minutes on the elliptical trainer and then did circuit training for 20 minutes, her fitness app says she burned 278 calories. When she spent 20 minutes on the elliptical trainer and 30 minutes circuit training she burned 473 calories. How many calories does she burn for each minute on the elliptical trainer?",
    "final_answer": 11.2,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Joni left St. Louis on the interstate, driving west towards Denver at a speed of 65 miles per hour. Half an hour later, Kelly left St. Louis on the same route as Joni, driving 78 miles per hour. How many hours will it take Kelly to catch up to Joni?",
    "final_answer": 2.5,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A river cruise ship sailed 60 miles downstream for 4 hours and then took 5 hours sailing upstream to return to the dock. Find the speed of the ship in still water, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 13.5,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A private jet can fly 1095 miles in three hours with a tailwind but only 987 miles in three hours into a headwind. Find the speed of the jet in still air, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 347,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A married couple together earn $75,000. The husband earns $15,000 more than five times what his wife earns. What does the wife earn?",
    "final_answer": 10000,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Daniela invested a total of $50,000, some in a certificate of deposit (CD) and the remainder in bonds. The amount invested in bonds was $5000 more than twice the amount she put into the CD. How much did she invest in the CD?",
    "final_answer": 15000,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In her last two years in college, Marlene received $42,000 in loans. The first year she received a loan that was $6,000 less than three times the amount of the second year’s loan. What was the amount of her loan for the first year?",
    "final_answer": 30000,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alyssa is twelve years older than her sister, Bethany. The sum of their ages is forty-four. Find Alyssa's age.",
    "final_answer": 28,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The age of Noelle’s dad is six less than three times Noelle’s age. The sum of their ages is seventy-four. Find Noelle’s dad's age.",
    "final_answer": 54,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two containers of gasoline hold a total of fifty gallons. The big container can hold ten gallons less than twice the small container. How many gallons does the big container hold?",
    "final_answer": 30,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shelly spent 10 minutes jogging and 20 minutes cycling and burned 300 calories. The next day, Shelly swapped times, doing 20 minutes of jogging and 10 minutes of cycling and burned the same number of calories. How many calories were burned for each minute of jogging?",
    "final_answer": 10,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Troy and Lisa were shopping for school supplies. Each purchased different quantities of the same notebook and thumb drive. Troy bought four notebooks and five thumb drives for $116. Lisa bought two notebooks and three thumb dives for $68. Find the cost of each notebook.",
    "final_answer": 4,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sarah left Minneapolis heading east on the interstate at a speed of 60 mph. Her sister followed her on the same route, leaving two hours later and driving at a rate of 70 mph. How many hours will it take for Sarah’s sister to catch up to Sarah?",
    "final_answer": 12,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the end of spring break, Lucy left the beach and drove back towards home, driving at a rate of 40 mph. Lucy’s friend left the beach for home 30 minutes (half an hour) later, and drove 50 mph. How many hours did it take Lucy’s friend to catch up to Lucy?",
    "final_answer": 2,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Jones family took a 12 mile canoe ride down the Indian River in two hours. After lunch, the return trip back up the river took three hours. Find the rate of the canoe in still water, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 5,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A motor boat traveled 18 miles down a river in two hours but going back upstream, it took 4.5 hours due to the current. Find the rate of the motor boat in still water, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 6.5,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A small jet can fly 1,072 miles in 4 hours with a tailwind but only 848 miles in 4 hours into a headwind. Find the speed of the jet in still air, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 240,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A commercial jet can fly 868 miles in 2 hours with a tailwind but only 792 miles in 2 hours into a headwind. Find the speed of the jet in still air, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 415,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The box office at a movie theater sold 147 tickets for the evening show, and receipts totaled $1,302. A child ticket costs $8, and an adult ticket costs $11. How many $11 adult tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 42,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Carson wants to make 20 pounds of trail mix using nuts and chocolate chips. His budget requires that the trail mix costs him $7.60 per pound. Nuts cost $9.00 per pound and chocolate chips cost $2.00 per pound. How many pounds of nuts should he use?",
    "final_answer": 16,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tickets to a Broadway show cost $35 for adults and $15 for children. The total receipts for 1650 tickets at one performance were $47,150. How many adult tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 1120,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tickets for a train cost $10 for children and $22 for adults. Josie paid $1,200 for a total of 72 tickets. How many children’s tickets did Josie buy?",
    "final_answer": 32,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tickets for a dance recital cost $15 for adults and $7 for children. The dance company sold 253 tickets and the total receipts were $2,771. How many adult tickets were sold?",
    "final_answer": 125,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cashier has 30 bills, all of which are $10 or $20 bills. The total value of the money is $460. How many of the  $10 bill does the cashier have?",
    "final_answer": 14,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hannah has to make twenty-five gallons of punch for a potluck. The punch is made of soda and fruit drink. The cost of the soda is $1.79 per gallon and the cost of the fruit drink is $2.49 per gallon. Hannah’s budget requires that the punch cost $2.21 per gallon. How many gallons of soda does she need?",
    "final_answer": 10,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Julia and her husband own a coffee shop. They experimented with mixing a City Roast Columbian coffee that cost $7.80 per pound with French Roast Columbian coffee that cost $8.10 per pound to make a 20 pound blend. Their blend should cost them $7.92 per pound. How much of City Roast Columbian coffee should they buy?",
    "final_answer": 12,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jotham needs 70 liters of a 50% alcohol solution. He has a 30% and an 80% solution available. How many liters of the 30% solution should he mix to make the 50% solution?",
    "final_answer": 42,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A scientist needs 65 liters of a 15% alcohol solution. She has available a 25% and a 12% solution. How many liters of the 25% solution should she mix to make the 15% solution?",
    "final_answer": 15,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 40% antifreeze solution is to be mixed with a 70% antifreeze solution to get 240 liters of a 50% solution. How many liters of the 40% solution will be used?",
    "final_answer": 160,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Laurie was completing the treasurer’s report for her son’s Boy Scout troop at the end of the school year. She didn’t remember how many boys had paid the $15 full-year registration fee and how many had paid the $10 partial-year fee. She knew that the number of boys who paid for a full-year was ten more than the number who paid for a partial-year. If $250 was collected for all the registrations, how many boys had paid the full-year fee?",
    "final_answer": 14,
    "section": "Solve Mixture Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "LaVelle is making a pitcher of caffe mocha. For each ounce of chocolate syrup, she uses five ounces of coffee. How many ounces of chocolate syrup does she need to make 48 ounces of caffe mocha?",
    "final_answer": 8,
    "section": "Solve Systems of Equations by Graphing",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Last month Jim and Debbie earned $7,200. Debbie earned $1,600 more than Jim earned. How much did Debbie earn?",
    "final_answer": 4400,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pam is 3 years older than her sister, Jan. The sum of their ages is 99. Find Pam's age.",
    "final_answer": 51,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sheila and Lenore were driving to their grandmother’s house. Lenore left one hour after Sheila. Sheila drove at a rate of 45 mph, and Lenore drove at a rate of 60 mph. How many hours will it take for Lenore to catch up to Sheila?",
    "final_answer": 3,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Marcus can drive his boat 36 miles down the river in three hours but takes four hours to return upstream. Find the rate of the boat in still water, in miles per hour.",
    "final_answer": 10.5,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lynn paid a total of $2,780 for 261 tickets to the theater. Student tickets cost $10 and adult tickets cost $15. How many student tickets did Lynn buy?",
    "final_answer": 227,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Yumi wants to make 12 cups of party mix using candies and nuts. Her budget requires the party mix to cost her $1.29 per cup. The candies are $2.49 per cup and the nuts are $0.69 per cup. How many cups of candies should she use?",
    "final_answer": 4,
    "section": "Solve Applications with Systems of Equations",
    "source": "Access for free at openstax.org. https://openstax.org/details/books/elementary-algebra-2e"
  }
]